Adam Rose

Data Scientist

Data scientist with an algorithmic and statistics based maths background, with experience as a data analyst deriving data analytics and insights: creating specialised analysis libraries, visualisations and coding tools to optimise my way of working. I revel in new challenges and have a passion for learning new things like finding new ways of doing tasks in the most efficient and effective way.

adam.p.rose1@gmail.com

07427066296

Princes Risborough, United Kingdom

in linkedin.com/in/adam-rose28

EDUCATION

MMath Mathematics University of Southampton

10/2017 - 06/2021

Master's thesis:

 Optimising the k-HC algorithm for modern spatial branch and bound solvers 1st Class Honours

A-Levels

Aylesbury Grammar School

06/2016 - 05/2017

Subjects:

Mathematics : A*Business Studies : B

- Further Mathematics : A*

- Applied ICT: C

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data analyst Oxehealth

06/2021 - Present

Sole data analyst in the Insights & benefits team, which allowed me to learn a wide spectrum of analytical and coding tricks to cover all our data problems. While at Oxehealth I revolutionised the role from my predecessor developing analytic tools and libraries to significantly reduce the time taken on analytic tasks.

Tasks / Accomplishments

- Managing the company's internal and customer data.
- Providing insights and statistics for non-technical team members.
- Developing statistical approaches to match a customer's desired insights, such that they are statistically sufficient for journals and publications.
- Creating specialised analysis libraries in python, this resulted in our data analysis tasks taking 4 - 12 hours instead of 4 - 6 weeks.
- Used Excel to create an automatic output tables system which imported data insights and summaries from the python libraries directly into tables.
- Created a series of automation scripts to streamline many of the data processes within the team.
- Extended my job role to collaborate with other technical teams as a result of automating most of my original role.

Teaching AssistantUniversity of Southampton

10/2019 - 05/2021

During term time the University employed me to help teach first and second year students doing similar mathematics courses.

Tasks

- Have a good understanding of a wide range of mathematics and solving relevant problems
- Interact with students identifying their weakness and areas which they need help with.
- Explain technical concepts in a simple and easy to grasp way.

SKILLS

Problem Solving Data analytics

Data Management Automation

Python Excel

Optimisation / Efficiency

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Stocks Modelling (09/2021 - Present)

- Creating and developing basic quant strategies for various S&P 500 stocks with back testing on the previous 20 years
- Creating analytical tools to analyse and spot trends the stock data to help identify possible quant strategies.

Crypto Modelling & Analysis (10/2021 - Present)

 Analysing crypto-currency data on short time intervals and making short term strategies on the Binance API

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Udemy (08/2021 - Present)

Completed / undertaking various course in Machine learning, coding, and data analytics and visualisation.

LANGUAGES

Python

Full Professional Proficiency

F

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

